[
    {
        "question": "1) What is Microsoft Access database?",
        "answer": "Microsoft Access database is a relational database management system which combines GUI (Graphical User Interface) with Microsoft Jet database engine. It can import and use data from Access, SQL, Oracle, etc.\nThis software is used to build application software.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) What is the way to link the explicit data into Access database?",
        "answer": "Follow the instructions given below to link explicit data into Access database:\nADVERTISEMENT\nGo to main menu and click on EXTERNAL DATA within Import and Link group.\nImport the required file.\nFollow the instruction in the Get External Data wizard to know about the file that can link Access database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) What are the several file extensions in MS Access?",
        "answer": "Following are the six file extensions in MS Access:\nAccess workgroup.mdw\nAccess database.accdb\nAccess Workgroup.mdw\nAccess blank project template.adn\nAccess project.adp\nProtected access database.accde",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "4) What is maximum size for an Access database?",
        "answer": "Maximum size of Access 2.0 version database is 1 gigabyte.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) Which technique is used to increase the size of database?",
        "answer": "Replication is used to increase the size of database.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) Tell some of the most important uses of MS Access?",
        "answer": "Uses of MS Access:\nMS Access is used as frontend when the backend is product of ODBC compliant.\nMS Access is widely used for small database applications are based on web and hosted on IIS by making use of ASP.NET pages.\nMainly, it is used by small firms and businesses, specific departments in large organizations and some people for developing applications on desktop for data applications.\nIt can be used as RAD while developing standalone applications and prototype.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What is a super key? How is it different from a candidate key?",
        "answer": "A superkey is a set of attributes within a table whose values can be used to uniquely identify a tuple. On the other hand, a candidate key is a minimal set of attributes mandatory to identify a tuple.\nA candidate key is also called a minimal super key.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "8) What are the various type of relations between different data?",
        "answer": "The data within the table can build only three types of relationships:\nOne-to-one relationship: This relationship specifies that only one item of table can link to one item of another table.\nOne-to-many relationship: This relationship specifies that one item of a table can corresponds to more than one item of another table.\nMany-to-many relationship: This relationship specifies that more than one item of a table can corresponds to more than one item of another table",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What are the protection features of MS Access?",
        "answer": "MS Access protection features are used to protect some documents by locking them. If you do not want to change some document then you can lock the document containing data and its code from modifications by changing file system extension to .MDE. Only the MDE extension files can be changed. One can find specific tools in the market that can be used to decompile and unlock code but changes made to VB scripts are permanent.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) How can you maintain a relationship between different databases in Access?",
        "answer": "Whenever a relationship is established between different databases, the first table of one database considered as a primary key whereas the new field in another database considered as a foreign key.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What are queries in MS Access?",
        "answer": "Queries can be seen as a request used to perform various operations on data such as sort data, insert data, retrieve data, update data, delete data, etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) How to create a simple query in MS Access 2013?",
        "answer": "Follow these instructions to create a simple query:\nOpen database.\nClick on -create tab.\nGo to query wizard icon.\nSelect a query type.\nSelect the appropriate table from the pull-down menu.\nNow, choose the required field in the query results.\nYou can insert information from additional tables, by repeating step 5 and 6.\nGo to next.\nChoose the result that you would like to produce.\nSpecify a title to your query.\nNow, click finish.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "13) How can you export data in Excel format?",
        "answer": "Follow the below steps to export data in Excel format:\nClick on toolbar and follow the External Data tab.\nNow, go to Excel on the Export group.\nAfter that excel spreadsheet dialog box will be opened on your screen.\nNow, it is required to provide destination of the file name and format.\nClick OK. Now data will be exported to Excel spreadsheet.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) How a table can be created using Microsoft Access Object Library (MAOL)?",
        "answer": "Define a variable of type object and initialize it with CreateTableDef() method.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "15) How can you create a form in MS Access 2013?",
        "answer": "Follow these instructions to create a form:\nGo to specific table you want to use to create a form.\nClick on Create tab and then locate the Forms group.\nClick the Form Command after which a form will be created and opened in Layout view.\nClick Save on the Quick Access toolbar and save the file with a specific name.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) What is the use of Pivot table?",
        "answer": "Pivot table is used for improving the presentation of data. By using Pivot table, you can view data multi-dimensionally. A Pivot table can summarize the data by categories and display trends spread over a range of categories.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What are the several methods to enter data in MS Access 2013?",
        "answer": "Different methods to enter data in MS Access are:\nUsing SQL View\nUsing form\nDatasheet View",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) Would you easily automate your MS Access database through menu driven selections?",
        "answer": "You can do it by creating a form with customized buttons that point to macros. An easier way is to use MS Access' built in function called \"Switchboard Manager\". This can be located in Tools/Add-Ins.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What is the role of WHERE clause in MS Access?",
        "answer": "WHERE clause is used with the SELECT statement to retrieve a value with certain criteria.\nWHERE clause can be used to join different fields of dissimilar data types by using LIKE keywords where one field is treated as a criteria for another field.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) What are the advantages of MS Access over MS SQL Server?",
        "answer": "Following are some of the advantages of MS Access over MS SQL Server:\nMS Access is much easier to handle.\nMS Access is more reliable as client can read and write directly into raw data table.\nMS Access is more scalable when number of users are less.\nMS Access is cheaper and more compatible.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "microsoft-access"
    }
]